Krisztina Pap



krisztina.pap@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/krisztinapap



780-644-0492



https://krisztinapap.github.io/portfolio-project/

Summary

I have been a remote worker for the past 8 years with a strong background in training, project management, and tech. I'm self-motivated, adaptable, and love a good challenge. I enjoy developing and maintaining high-quality code for interesting projects both independently and as part of a team.

I joined the intensive, 6-month Software Developer training program, TECHCareers, to help turn my passion for programming into a career - My goal is to write code for a living!

Experience



Freelance Work/Portfolio Building

Self-Employed

Jan 2012 - Present (8 years 9 months +)

I have been working online as a remote contractor since 2012 when I decided to stay home with my kids. Since then, I have done a variety of freelance work from teaching English as a Second Language (I am a certified ESL instructor) and training development to one-off editing, web development, and research projects.

Web Development:

- Created mock-ups, wire frames, and low, medium, and high-fidelity prototypes
- Created digital assets for YouTube content producers
- Built several websites using technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress, Bootstrap, Sass, TailwindCSS, and React.js
- Completed practice data science projects (data manipulation and visualization, and basic machine learning) using technologies such as Python, Jupyter Notebooks, R, pandas, sklearn, and matplotlib

Consulting work:

- Completed risk-assessments covering topics such as physical safety and security; federal/provincial/industry regulations, law, and best practice compliance; staff skill gaps and succession-planning; and training processes and tools
- Re-evaluated existing processes and procedures; re-defined company roles and positions
- Analyzed client needs; liaised with stakeholders
- Researched technologies, best practices, and software options with consideration to tight budgets and security concerns

Training Development:

- Developed training (live and modules)
- Developed and presented plans and storyboards (including budgets, physical and human resource requirements, and timelines)
- Developed eLearning Management System structure
- Developed learning paths and individual course learning objectives (for each department and individual role)
- Created and edited all necessary video and audio files
- Created online quizzes and tests to measure student performance and to ensure previously established training goals were met

- Conducted user testing before and after course launches
- Monitored student performance and assisted in change and performance management

■★D English as a Second Language Instructor

VIPKid

Mar 2014 - Mar 2020 (6 years 1 month)

Since March of 2014, I have completed a number of 6-month contracts with some of the most prestigious English as a Second Language providers in the industry. I am a certified TESOL/TEFL Specialist with hundreds of hours of professional development courses under my belt.

- I delivered thousands of 1-on-1 and group (up to 8 students in a classroom) ESL classes over video chat
- I taught a wide variety of students from children as young as 4-years-old to accomplished adults who worked as elementary school teachers, physicians, research scientists, and businessmen/women in various parts of Asia and South America
- I administered skill placement tests and assessments, and tailored my teaching approach to each situation in that moment
- I provided detailed reports based on my professional observations, complete with specific recommendations to improve fluency levels, after each class to every single student I taught

Executive Associate

Alberta Health Services

Dec 2016 - Jan 2018 (1 year 2 months)

In December of 2016, I accepted a full-time position as the Executive Associate to the North Zone Medical Director of Alberta Health Services. The position involved a lot of political networking and long drives up North, so ultimately, I didn't feel that it was a good match for me, and I resigned a year later. That said, I may not have felt fullfilled by the work but I did gain a much deeper understanding of our healthcare system!

- I managed the various action requests, patient concerns, and other issues that a Zone Medical Director (ZMD) is required to investigate, address, and respond to
- I played a key role in setting and creating planning timelines and guidelines based on portfolio priorities, building office supports, systems and processes
- I lead/coordinated various projects within the portfolio as assigned
- I researched complex issues and drafted briefing notes and reports as required
- I was responsible for the administration, coordination, and management of the committees that the ZMD or another senior physician leader chaired or co-chaired

Weekend Time Entry Lead

North American Construction Group

Jun 2014 - Nov 2015 (1 year 6 months)

From June of 2014 to November of 2015, I was the Weekend Time Entry Lead at North American Construction Group's Acheson office. As my team and I mostly just worked weekends, I was able to stay home and homeschool my kids during the week.

- I entered data with superb speed and accuracy
- I managed a time/financial data entry team of five
- I on-boarded new employees

- I handled a variety of emergencies

Freelance Consultant/Training Specialist

J. Ennis Fabrics, Oxford Childcare, and various online content creators

Jan 2010 - Jun 2014 (4 years 6 months)

From January of 2010 to June of 2014, I worked as a Training Coordinator/Freelance Consultant. I started full-time at J. Ennis Fabrics, switching to part-time remote work after a year and a half.

- I collaborated with managers and supervisors to create training, process, and procedure manuals for existing positions
- I assisted in developing the new employee training program
- I assessed skill levels and provided one-on-one training as needed for hundreds of employees
- I implemented a web-based Learning Management System (including curriculum development and building of the required training modules)

Education



University of Alberta

Certificate, Full Stack Software Developer 2020 - 2021

Government of Alberta / TECHCareers

MacEwan University

Bachelor of Applied Human Services Administration Degree 2012 - 2014

Received Dean's Medal for Academic Excellence



MacEwan University

Investigations and Risk Management Diploma 2004 - 2006

Licenses & Certifications



(A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification (300 hours) - freeCodeCamp

IT Security Foundations: Core Concepts - Project Management Institute 7E6371388D8A44E7A6A620DFFFFFACA3

Skills

Front-end Development • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Data Science • Web Development • User Experience (UX) • JavaScript • C# • Full-Stack Development • React.js